

Htet Myet Lwin FULLSTACK DEVELOPER 28 years old

- Pangkok, Thailand
- htetmyetlwin263@gmail.co
- +66 640324760
- +66 640324760
- portfolio-hml.onrender.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/htetmyet-lwin-561279181

AWARDS

Job Matching Hackathon 2023

Leading as a mentor (Second Price Winning Team)

SKILLS

Software Development
Project Management
Problem Solving
Creativity
Leadership

PROFILE

Experienced and energetic Software Developer with over six years of experience effectively managing websites, web applications, and software development projects from conception to completion.

In my current role as a Full Stack Developer at Wun Wun Lat - IT solution (remote), I successfully led the development of software, Website, Web development and mobile development that increased sales. I am confident that my strong problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and ability to work under pressure would enable me to contribute to the success.

FRAMEWORK & TOOLS

- NodeJs, ReactJs, Python, Java, C#, PHP
- MySQL, Postgresql, MongoDB
- API Development (Laravel, ExpressJS, NodeJS)
- GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket, AWS, Digital Ocean

DETAIL SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5, JavaScript,
 jQuery, WordPress, and woocommerce.
- Responsive Design for any platform size.
- UI/UX: Figma, Adobe XD, Adobe PhotoshopCS6, Adobe illustrator CC 2019, and bootstrap studio.
- Database management system (MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL).
- Code and Deploy Applications in a crossplatform, Cross-Brower Environment with AWS, Cpanel.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

WUN WUN LAT CO.,LTD (IT SOLUTION)

Jul 2023 - Present

At Wun Wun Lat Company (Remote), I spearheaded multifaceted development projects from inception to deployment, leveraging my expertise in both frontend and backend technologies. My role involved collaborating closely with cross-functional teams, guiding junior developers, and architecting scalable solutions to meet business objectives.

Technologies Used:

Frontend: React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5, Tailwind, JavaScript (ES6+), Wordpress, Woocommerce

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Python, Django, Flask, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL

DevOps: Docker, GitLab CI/CD, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Digital Ocean, Z.com

Tools: Git, JIRA, Confluence, Postman, VS Code, PyCharm

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

MODUS OPERANDI CO.,LTD - FINTECH COMPANY

May 2021 - Jul 2023

- Design, develop, and implement software solutions using languages such as Java, Python, and PHP.
- Work with cross-functional teams to understand project requirements, identify technical challenges, and provide solutions.
- Utilize Agile methodologies, Git, JIRA, and other tools to manage software development processes and workflows.
- Developed and maintained multiple microservices that are part of a larger cloud-based platform.
- Built and deployed scalable and secure applications to AWS.
- Implemented new features and enhancements to improve the overall user experience and performance.
- Mentored junior engineers and provided technical guidance and support.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPEMENT TEAM LEAD, SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

RITZ CYBER INTELLIGENCE SERVICES CO.,LTD

Mar 2018 - Apr 2021

- Developing and maintaining the functionality of Websites, Web Applications, Domain and Hosting.
- Participating in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.
- Designing prototypes for Web Apps and Websites.
- Manage team members and evaluate their performance.
- Manage and Prioritize Multiple Projects.
- Providing technical support to endusers.
- Experience Projects: Condo Management System, Microfinance System,
 Content Management, System Websites, Construction site database system,
 Fashion School Management System, Online Shopping

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, JUNIOR PROGRAMMER

MYANMAR ORIENTAL BANK - BANKING INDUSTRY

Mar 2017 - Jan 2018

- Assisted senior developers in designing and coding website features using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Contributed to the development of a new HR Management System with PHP language.
- Improved website performance by optimizing images and improving page load time.
- Developed custom WordPress themes and plugins.
- Assisted in migrating websites from one server to another
- Collaborated with designers and other stakeholders to understand project requirements and provide solutions.
- Version Control of Tortoise SVN, Git.
- Content Management System with WordPress.

EXPERIENCE PROJECTS

Content Management System, Mobile Application Development, E-commerce Management System, Inventory Management Application, Logistic Warehouse Management Application, Biller Configuration, Risk Report and Transaction Report.

Condo Management System, Microfinance System, Content Management System Websites, Construction site database system, Fashion School Management System,

Online Shopping Product management system, Share files Application, Employee Management System, Online Learning Management System.

HR Management System, Bank Website, Contact Form Application, and data management system.

Live Website URL:

https://globalvisaconsultants.net.mm/

https://beyondofficialmm.com/

https://mo.com.mm/

https://powerpros.com.mm/

EDUCATION HISTORY

WEST YANGON TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY

2012-2017

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (BE-IT)

Major — Information Technology

GUSTO INTERNATIONAL COLLEGE

2017-2018

CERTIFIED IN PHP WEB DEVELOPMENT

LOGIC UNION TRAINING CLASS

2017

CERTIFIED IN WEB DESIGN

KMD COMPUTER CENTER

2012-2013

CERTIFIED IN PRACTICAL A+

SEAMEO CHAT

DIPLOMA IN ENGLISH LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

ACTIVITIES

- Identify user and system requirements for new websites and applications.
- Prioritize software development projects, set timelines, and assign tasks to team members.
- Manage team members and evaluate their performances.
- Collaborate with mobile developers to build APIs integration for web applications.
- Handle Frequent Feedback.
- Attention to Detail.
- Self-starter Attitude, Strong Problem Solver, works well under Pressure.